Guide to the J. Myron Atkin Papers SC1390
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
J. Myron Atkin Papers
1980-2003
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Atkin, J. Myron
SC1390
61 Linear Feet (116 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, notes, conference papers and agenda, grant applications, financial records, and printed matter, relating primarily to science education in the United States.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 2017. Accession 2018-083 acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981 & transferred to Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives, Stanford University Libraries, 2018.
Biographical/Historical Note
American educator.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, notes, conference papers and agenda, grant applications, financial records, and printed matter, relating primarily to science education in the United States.
Science--Study and teaching.; Education--United States.; Education.; Atkin, J. Myron
- Papers
  - EDUC 358 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EDUC 358 - Research Base (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 397X Fall, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 397 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Control Classroom Research (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 397X Aut, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 397 Autumn, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hum Bio 117, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Doctoral Seminar Cuban (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 444 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 300X (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - C+I Winter, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 267B Winter, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 267B Winter, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - RIP Fall, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 267B, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - TAE Wook Winter, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 267 Summer, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - CTE Seminar, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 267 Sum, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 267A Summer, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 267A Summer, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - C+I Summer, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 267B Winter, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - EDUC 355X (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 267 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - STEP Class, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - STEP Synner Project Proposal -> Prof. Atteins MESA Analysis (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - HUM Bio Spring, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - HUM BIO WINT, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - HUM BIO (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - HUM BIO 117 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - HUMAN BIO 117 WINT 90, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - HUM BIO Papers (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - HUMBIO 117 88-89, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 355A Autumn, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - EDUC 355X (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - HUM BIO 00, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - HUM BIO 117 Winter, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 297B - Winter, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 232B - Fall, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - ED232C Sp., 2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 267 SUMMER 97, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 267 Summer Readings (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - New Curric. Course 232B - Winter, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - ED 347 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - TAMIR (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 267A Summer, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - EDUC 359C Fall, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - EDUC 359C, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 359b Fall, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2018-083
  - Stanford and the Schools project (Box 1-8)
  - Carnegie Corporation project (Box 9-18)
  - Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development project (Box 19-27)
  - National Research Council. Mathematical Sciences Education Board (Box 28-29)
  - National Assessment of Educational Progress (Box 30)
  - National Assessment of Educational Progress (Box 31)
  - College Board
  - National Research Council. National Committee on Science Education Standards and Assessment (Box 32)
  - Youth Alive! (Box 33)
  - Youth Alive! (Box 34)
  - Education Development Center
  - United States. Public Health Service (Box 35)
  - Industry Initiatives for Science and Math Education
  - Miscellaneous projects (Box 36-37)
  - Miscellaneous projects (Box 38)
  - Correspondence
  - Correspondence (Box 39-40)
  - Incremental Materials (Box 41-113)
    Scope and Contents
    This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu